if they came out with a new rule that
said I could only trade one trading
strategy for the rest of my trading
career then the market structure trading
strategy you're going to learn in this
video would be the one I would choose
Market structure can be one of the most
powerful tools you have in your trading
Arsenal but if you use it incorrectly if
you don't know how to identify swing
lows and swing highs correctly or you
don't know how to identify the most
accurate levels of structure to trade
around or you just simply don't know how
to create profitable trading
opportunities around Market structure
then they're going to be completely
useless and could even cause detrimental
losses into your account so for that
reason in this video I'm going to be
sharing with you my top three Market
structure trading strategies we'll go
all the way from the basics of
identifying swing highs and swing lows
correctly to identifying the proper
levels to trade around and to creating
profitable trading opportunities around
those levels so if this is something
you've been struggling with then this
video is for you and if that sounds
interesting go a and click that like
button for me go ahead and subscribe to
the channel if you're new and I'll see
you right after the intro and
[Music]
disclaimer welcome back let's go ahead
and get started the first thing you're
going to need to know how to do is
properly identify major swing eyes and
major swing lows this is a pivotal part
of you being able to spot major levels
of structure correctly so let's go ahead
and dive into that right now looking on
the chart you can see the most
simplistic version of major major swing
lows and major swing highs in an uptrend
we have major swing highs and then the
major swing low this major swing low is
the bottom of the pullback from the
major swing High then the highest point
after the break of the previous major
swing high is our next major swing high
so this is the level before the pullback
starts then once the pullback starts the
bottom of that pullback is going to be
our major swing low then if we break
above our previous major swing high at
the point that the pullback starts is
our next major swing high at the point
that it ends or the bottom of the
pullback is our next major swing low the
opposite is true for a downtrend here we
have a reversal going from a major swing
High breaking below our previous major
swing low which identifies a reversal
situation in the market then we have a
new major swing low and the top of the
pullback before the continuation down is
our major swing High the bottom of our
impulsive move before the pullback
starts is our major swing low and the
top of that pullback would be our major
swing High that's the most simplistic
way to explain major swing highs and
major swing lows but this isn't what
they look like on a chart if we compare
this picture and we scroll down to
actual price data the chart here looks
nearly nothing like this and the reason
is because there's not always going to
be all green candles in your impulsive
move up and there's not always going to
be all red candles in your pullback and
that's what this diagram kind of depicts
so in order to keep from being confused
when we go down to real price we need to
create some really set in stone rules
around major swing highs and lows let's
do that right now so let's talk about
the problems with diagram number one
first off we're going to talk about
pullbacks pullbacks rarely ever are just
all red candles followed by an impulsive
move that breaks the previous major
structure High what do pullbacks
actually look like most of the time well
most of the time they have smaller
Trends inside of them they may have
multiple minor swing lows and highs
before they go and break above the
previous major structure high so here's
what it's important to realize in our
first rule we're going to discuss is
about these pullbacks when we have an
uptrend started we have the initial move
to our major swing High followed by the
pullback to our major swing low followed
by an impulsive move up to our next
major swing High the important thing to
realize is that between
our major swing low down here and our
major swing high right here everything
that happens during this pullback as
long as price does not close below our
major swing low is just the pullback of
this uptrend everything that happens in
between we can have consolidation for
days on days on days as long as we don't
close below that level our previous
major swing low then we're still just in
an uptrend and all of this is just part
part of the pullback of that uptrend so
that's rule number one to keep in mind
and the second problem with the previous
diagram is that it assumes every
impulsive move that goes higher is just
a straight line when in reality after
this break often times what do we see we
see small pullbacks one candle maybe two
candles pulling back these for me would
not qualify as major swing lows so a
rule I created in order to identify
swing lows and highs correctly is that
in order to have a major swing low from
our major swing High wherever that is
created I need at least a three candle
pullback from that level meaning if
we're an uptrend and this is one candle
pullback and this is two candle pullback
then I don't count anything as a major
structure High yet and I wait until I
get at least a three candle pullback
before identifying this as our new major
structure high and then once this level
is
broken since this was in fact a three
candle pullback now I have a new major
structure low so what our first rule
does is ensures that we're not marking
off false major swing highs and lows
during pullbacks when there's just minor
swing highs and lows and the second rule
ensures that during our impulsive move
if we have these tiny little pullbacks
we're not going to pay attention to
those we're going to wait for the major
pullback and the major pullback is
identified by at least three red candles
in the pullback during an uptrend and
they do not need to be consecutive it
can be green candle it could be red
candle green candle two more red candles
it doesn't have to be all three in a row
but we just need to see at least three
red candles in this pullback to identify
this as our major structure high and
this as our major structure low now
let's take a look at a bearish version
of this in our bearish version we have a
major structure High pulling down to a
major structure low a lower high here
with our major structure High and a push
below this major structure low putting
us into a downtrend now if we
have a tiny pullback of one candle right
here is this now our major structure low
and this our new major structure High
hopefully you answered no remember
during our impulsive move in this
bearish trend we need to see at least a
three candle pullback let's say this is
a three candle pullback and at this
point when we have that three candle
pullback is when we can identify this
level as our new major structure low now
after this three candle pullback there
could be as many candles as the market
desires but it needs to be at least
three green candles in a bearish trend
after that we have to wait for now the
close below this previous major
structure level to identify this as our
new major structure high now let me ask
you this if during this pullback we have
a situation like this have we now
started a new
uptrend the answer would be no remember
everything between our major structure
load that was created by the fact that
we had a three candle pullback to the
bullish Direction and our previous major
structure High which was the start of
our impulsive move pushing lower during
this impulsive move we cannot look at
one or two candle pullbacks as major
swing levels so during this impulsive
move from this major swing High to this
major swing low all that's in between
this is going to be the pullback of a
downtrend no matter how much
consolidation happens all of this is
just the pullback in the midst of a
current
downtrend so now that you know how to
identify swing highs and swing lows
correctly understanding these strategies
is going to be extremely simple that's
what we're going to jump into right now
and do not worry if you're still a
little bit confused about identifying
these swing highs and lows we're going
to go through a lot of examples of these
as I dissect and teach you these three
trading strategies now these three
trading strategies are going to be
ranked kind of like the Olympics we're
going to have a gold level strategy a
silver level strategy and a bronze level
strategy let's get started with the gold
level strategy this is a strategy that
I've seen to be the most accurate Market
structure-based strategy I've ever
traded and I call it the trend reversal
structure strategy or trss for sure
short in the most simplistic version of
this strategy this is what we're going
to be looking for we'll be looking for a
market that is in a downtrend this is a
bullish version of this by the way we'll
be looking for a market in a downtrend
we'll then be looking for the break of
the previous major structure high and
that will be our Trend reversal level
when price comes down to that major
structure High we're going to be looking
for possible buy trades in that area and
the reason this tends to work so well is
one that it's very accurate and two it
gives us the opportunity to jump on the
start of a new uptrend which obviously
means we can get a really good reward to
risk ratio if we catch these correctly
but identifying swing lows and eyes
correctly is the first step so let's go
ahead and go down to the chart and take
a look at this strategy on real markets
so we're going to start off by
identifying swing highs and lows on the
pound Swiss this is going to be our
starting point from here pushing up
where is our first swing High
hopefully you said this level right here
and what's the reason for that is
because after this level we have 1 two
three red candles coming down to our
swing low that's the only time we can
identify an actual major swing high and
major swing low so for that reason this
is what that will look like after that
we have a break Above This creating
another major swing High we then have a
pull down to a possible reversal a pull
back up to our major swing level and a
potential trading opportunity we're
going to look deeply at a trading
opportunity that's further to the right
I just wanted to point this out here
towards the beginning but next up what
do we have as we continue pointing out
our levels of structure we have a break
of our previous low right here and a
close below it down to our new structure
low after that we're going up to a new
structure high in this impulsive move up
where is our new structure High it would
be all the way up here we have other
small smaller pullbacks but none of them
meet the criteria for an actual pullback
based on our rules we need at least
three candles pulling back to classify
something as being a valid swing high or
low so in this case we have a new swing
High there pull back to a new swing low
push up to a new swing High we then have
a reversing situation as we reverse
would this be a new swing low and high
answer is no would this answer is also
no so what this would mean is the way we
would draw this structure in the way we
would draw our swing highs and lows is
from this swing High all the way down to
this swing low at this point anything
that happens between here and here is
just the pullback of a downtrend and I
know that's a large Zone but this is
just what happens when you read
structure correctly and identify swing
highs and lows correctly at times you're
going to have massive zones where price
can go before identifying the
continuation of trend or a possible
reversal in this case case we have a new
swing High pushing up here all this
again was just the pullback of that
downtrend we then push lower and right
here what do you notice we have our push
down to a low then we have more than
three candles in this pullback this
would be our next move to our major
swing High down to our major swing low
and this is exactly what we're looking
for everything between here this major
swing high and this major swing low is
going to be the pullback of this
downtrend but if we get a push lower we
have Trend continuation if that would
have happened this would be a trend
continuation situation that's a weird
thing to say out loud if we get a break
Above This Zone then we have what we
call a reversal situation during this
reversal situation is when we can
implement the trss strategy so the way
we would do that is after price pushes
above
this level we then want to create a zone
out of that level which would look
something like this and we want to see
if price eventually does in fact pull
back into that level which happens as
you can see right here so now we have a
perfect situation for the trss strategy
we had a downtrend we then have a break
of that structure level this is now a
pullback that's come back into this
structure level and let's see what
happens next next we get a bullish C
Candlestick pattern now this is what I
would consider an A+ setup for this
strategy and the reason is because not
only do we have the perfect
trss strategy happening we also have the
combination of this being a level that's
been tested multiple times looking left
and the third reason this is a A+ setup
is because we're also pushing off of the
50 period
EMA or exponential moving average so in
all three of those things combin with my
trss strategy I take this trade every
single time because it is the most
accurate Market structured trade I've
ever found so let's go ahead and click
play and as you can see this did in fact
cause a complete reversal and a new
bullish Trend now the next video I post
is going to be going over the exact
custom Candlestick pattern that I
utilize in these areas and in that video
I'll be going over the specific rules of
this Candlestick pattern and the stops
in targets for this entire strategy so
if you want to be alerted when that
video comes out be sure you're
subscribed here to the channel I don't
want to put that in this video because
it's already going to be extremely long
I want to make sure this video is all
about the structure levels now we're
going to take a look at a bearish
version of this strategy we're going to
start off here on the all New Zealand
down here at our swing low from That
Swing Low we're going to push up to the
highest point before a three candle
pullback so these little areas right
here would be minor pullbacks we would
not count those as swing lows and swing
highs at least not major ones we would
go up to this highest point before we
have a three candle or more pullback
which is right here this would now be
our new major swing low this would be
our major swing High down to our major
swing low up to our major swing High
important note anything between our new
major swing high and our new major swing
low is just consolidation it's just the
pullback of a bullish Trend it's the
pullback of the current uptrend we are
in in unless we get a close Above This
range which would then be Trend
continuation or a close below this range
which would then be a trend reversal so
with this being the case do we have what
we need to set up and to look for our
trss strategy the answer is yes at this
point we would just create a Zone here
at this previous major structure level
or major swing low right here the one
that was just broken by price after we
have our Zone in place we're going to be
waiting for price to pull back to this
Zone give us an entry reason and then
we're going to be looking to capture the
start of a downtrend from the reversal
of our previous uptrend so let's push
the price forward and see what happens
as you can see here price has pulled
back up into our Zone and in terms of
Entry we're just going to pretend we're
using a close below candle which is a
candle that just closes below the low
of the previous candle this is an entry
that works well with this trading
strategy in the first place so let's go
ahead and assume that's what we use we'd
be setting up a trade based on that
entry reason so after placing our entry
we would need to place a stop loss let's
go with 15 Pips since we're on the
4-Hour candle above our swing high right
here we have 16 Pips up to that swing
High we want to add 15 Pips to that that
would be 31 Pips on the stop loss and
I'm going to go with a 1.4 to1 reward
risk ratio just as an example on this
trade let's say we sell right there
let's see what happens with
price price eventually does in fact push
down far enough to hit those targets and
this level does in fact create a new
downtrend that as you can see lasted
quite a while and this is the beauty of
this trading strategy is the fact that
we can capture the start of a downtrend
which gives us the ability to capture a
really good reward to risk ratio so what
you just learned is what I consider the
golden strategy whenever it comes to
Market structure trading now what we're
going to do is take a look at what I
consider the silver strategy of Market
structure trading this strategy applies
the same concept of identifying swing
highs and lows that you learned earlier
in the video so it should be extremely
simple for you to understand since you
already know that part of the strategy
this strategy instead of capturing
reversals captures a trend that's
already started so let's go ahead and
take a look at a couple of examples and
I'll explain the entire rule set to you
for the silver trading strategy
utilizing Market structure let's go ah
and take a look at the chart now we're
on the Euro New Zealand we're just going
to point out the swing highs and lows at
first we're starting from our swing low
this broke above our previous High here
we have a swing High followed by our
pullback followed by a push up we need
the pullback to have at least three
candles so this is our actual new swing
High Why would this and this not be our
new swing high they both broke above our
previous swing high but they only have
two pullbacks in them so with that being
the case I don't count these as swing
highs or these as swing lows not major
ones at least they are minor swing highs
and lows but our major swing high is all
the way up here then we have more than a
three candle pullback pushing price to
our new swing low pushing us back up now
breaking above to a new swing High we
have more than a three candle pullback
here pushing us down to a new swing low
and a break and close above so at this
point we are in an established uptrend
while in an established uptrend is when
we're going to look for this trading
strategy the first step here is going to
be to identify the latest swing eye that
was broken after we have that identified
let me delete these lines to make this
really clear to see we're going to
create a zone out of that area so this
is what that zone would look like for me
now that's the first rule is that we
create a zone out of the latest swing
high that was broken the second rule is
that this level must have been tested at
least two times in the last
400 candles and the reason I used 400
candles in not a certain period of time
is because this strategy can be used on
any time frame and if we're looking back
let's say 3 months on a 4-Hour chart
that's going to be a wildly different
amount of candles than it will be if
we're looking back 3 months on a 5
minute chart so for that reason we're
just going to be looking back around 400
candles and 400 candles is around 3
months on the 4our chart we're on right
now so if we go back about 3 months or
so we can see that this level did in
fact get tested another time back here
so this validates my second rule that
the level of structure I'm utilizing for
Trend continuation has in fact been
tested multiple times now if these two
things come together if we have a swing
High that has just been broken and
closed above and this level's been
tested two times in the last 400 or so
candles then this is now a level I want
to pay attention to for Possible Trading
opportunities I want to wait for a
pullback into this level and any kind of
specific Candlestick pattern here on the
4-Hour chart like a hammer a close above
candle or a engulfing candle or I might
drop down to the 1eh hour chart and look
for things like double Bottoms in this
area but what I've done now is
identified a trend continuation Zone
that is likely to push the market into
Trend continuation by utilizing Market
structure so let's push price forward
and see what happens happens eventually
we get this really nice Hammer
Candlestick with a long Wick to the
bottom this would be a great reason for
entry for me and again we are utilizing
a few things here we're utilizing the
ability to point out swing highs and
lows correctly so that we know we're at
a major swing high with this level we're
utilizing a level of structure that's
been tested multiple times then we're
waiting for that area to be tested again
and waiting for some type of buying
pressure by utilizing Candlestick
patterns or chart patterns on a lower
time frame to enter at a logical place
to capture Trend continuation so with
all this being the case and everything
coming together this is where I would
place my entry my stop loss will be
under this swing low and for the targets
for these examples we've been using
about a 1.4 to1 reward to risk ratio if
I click play you can see that price
pushed up and hit that pretty easily now
in terms of this being a trend
continuation strategy If You're
Expecting actual Trend continuation and
this is another way that I like to
utilize taking targets if I'm around my
computer when this hits this 1.4 to1 I
just move my stop loss to break even
then I look left for the next level of
resistance price will hit if this trend
does continue higher and this will be my
actual targets and my stop loss again
will be moved to break even after that
1.4 to1 and even with those being the
targets you can see that those targets
were hit pretty easily as well but when
we're expecting train continuation it's
sometimes best to maximize the reward to
risk ratio we can get out of of a trade
because again what we're expecting is in
fact the continuation of this uptrend
and we're utilizing the power of Market
structure in order to pinpoint the
perfect area to jump on that Trend so
that was a bullish example of the silver
trading strategy utilizing Market
structure our Trend continuation
strategy now let's flip that upside down
and take a look at a bearish version of
this trading strategy if we start to
Mark out our Trend we have a swing High
down to a swing low up to a swing High
down to a swing low up to a swing high
and down to a swing low at this point
based on what you learned about the
bullish version of the strategy where
should we be looking for Possible
Trading opportunities it would be the
previous swing low that the market has
most recently broken and Clos below so
with that being the case we would draw
out a Zone in our area here of structure
based on our previous swing low that was
broken and in this area is where we
would like to look for trading
opportunities if all of our rules are
met what's the other rule we have to see
met this level must have been tested at
least two times in the last 400 candles
so if we scroll left let's see if that's
the case yes it is if we look left we
can see that this level has in fact been
tested multiple times as support in the
past so that validates the second rule
we have and that means that this area is
in fact an area we want to look for
Possible Trading opportunities inside of
for Trend continuation during this
bearish trend now another thing I want
to mention is you don't have to actually
count 400 candles whenever I say I want
to look back the latest 400 candles the
measuring tool on trading view you can
just grab it and click on the chart at
the most recent candle and then scroll
back left and it will show you as you
can see right here the amount of bars
you're going back this is 268 bars from
where I started to where I stopped the
measuring tool so that's the easier way
to measure 400 Bars instead of trying to
count 400 Bars which would take a
ridiculous amount of time but back to
the lesson here is the area we want to
pay attention to for Possible Trading
opportunities we want to see price get
into this area and see possible
Candlestick patterns or chart patterns
on a lower time frame let's take a look
at what happens so price pulls into this
area and we eventually get this big
close below candle showing a lot of
selling pressure from this area so we've
now combined Market structure
pinpointing the perfect area to get on
board with a trend continuation trade
and now we have selling pressure in that
area showing us that sellers are in fact
trying to take control that would give
me all I would need to place a sell
trade here and when I say a perfect
scenario I don't mean in any way that it
works out 100% of the time I'm just
saying this is the most logical way to
try to capture a trend it doesn't work
100% of the time I'll show you some
losing trades as well but these are EX
examples of winning trades obviously
because I'm teaching the strategy to you
right now let's go ahead and take a look
though so our stop loss would go above
the swing high and for these examples of
1.4 to1 reward to risk ratio we would be
taking a sell trade right there we would
then be waiting for price to either push
lower or higher and eventually price
does in fact push down enough to hit
those targets so one more look at our
silver market structure Trend
continuation strategy here we're on the
dollar Yen this is a trade I actually
played
last week we're currently on the daily
chart I already have this pointed out I
just want to show you this as an example
we have price pushing up to a swing High
then breaking and closing Above That
Swing high right over here then we look
at this level create a zone out of it in
our gray area we have this Zone being
tested multiple times even though this
was an inside level or a minor swing
High I do allow that to be one of the
times in terms of the multiple times
tested in our Market structure level so
with that being the case price then
pushed down and was even bouncing off of
the 50 EMA and just like our reversal
strategy this is what I consider an A+
setup for the trend continuation Market
structure strategy now with this being
the case I placed this trade last week
I'll go ahead and hit play and as you
can see I was just stopped out of this
trade so I just wanted to show this
trade to ensure that you understand that
this does not win 100% of the time no
strategy does the point of any trading
strategy is to have an edge over the
market that edge does not mean you know
exactly what the Market's going to do
every time you place a trade it just
means that over a long period of time if
you have over a 50% chance to win which
this does give me according to my
testing and trading of this strategy and
if you can get over a one to1 reward
risk ratio on those trades then you're
inevitably going to be profitable over a
long period of time that was our silver
trading strategy which is a trend
continuation strategy now let's talk
about the bronze Market Market structure
trading strategy that I like to utilize
now this is my least favorite out of the
three but it still provides a
significant Edge over the market
especially when you combine it with a
good reward to risk ratio or maximizing
your Targets on these types of Trades
let's go ahead and take a look at
examples of these and walk through the
rules of our bronze trading strategy
here we are on the New Zealand dollar on
this pair I'm going to start our Trend
off right down here swing low to high
down to new swing low up to new swing
High down new swing low up to new swing
High down to new swing low and then we
break and close again now just like all
the other strategies this utilizes our
format for identifying swing highs and
lows correctly but in this case for the
bronze trading strategy we're still
looking for Trend continuation but this
is more of a last chance to hop on the
trend type of scenario what I mean by
that is in this case let's say this
trade fails our Trend continuation trade
in this case it looks like it does if
this trade fails or if I do not get a
trade for Trend continuation out of our
swing High Zone then what I look at next
is the swing low before the break and
close into new swing highs so here is
that swing low before the breaking close
into a new swing high this is what I
consider the bronze level in terms of
Market structure trading and the reason
it's bronze is because although if we do
get a trading opportunity in this area
often times it can create a good reward
to risk scenario the downside of this is
if price is pulling all the way back to
our previous major swing low that's
actually a sign of weakness in the trend
so although it does work out enough
times to have an edge it is something
that comes with more losses than the
other two strategies but let's walk
through all of the rules first rule is
that the price must be pulling back to
or must pull back to the previous swing
low before price broke and closed above
the previous swing high so with that
being the case we have that rule met and
in the same scenario as our Trend
continuation strategy you just learned
we also need this level to have been
tested multiple times within the last
400 candles so in this case as you can
see we do have a level that's been
tested multiple times within the past
400 candles it's also the swing low in
our trending Market before the latest
break into new swing highs so with that
being the case this is going to be the
zone that I'm looking in for Possible
Trading opportunities so what I need to
see is price pull back to that zone and
once we get there I need a very similar
situation A Candlestick pattern on this
time frame the 4H hour chart or a chart
pattern like a double bottom on a
smaller time frame in this case what do
we get right here we get a nice long
Wick to the bottom side showing buying
pressure out of our Major Market
structure Zone and this buying pressure
could be enough to push price into new
struct highs or to continue the trend
which is why this is another Trend
continuation strategy so in this case we
would have a stop loss just below our
swing low we'll use a 1.4 again for the
targets and this would be our exact
trade setup this would be the exact
moment I would click the buy button for
my own trading and if we press play to
see what the market did we do in fact
push up high enough to hit those targets
eventually and this was a bullish
example of what I consider the bronze
Market structure trading strategy now
let's take a look at a bearish example
of this Market structure trading
strategy here we will start our Trend at
the top here pushing down to a swing low
up to a lower swing High down to a lower
swing low up to a lower swing High down
to a lower swing low in this specific
case based on what you learned about the
bullish version of the strategy what is
the Zone we would be looking in for
Possible Trading opportunities well it
would be the previous swing high before
the break into a new swing low with that
that being the case we're going to take
a line tool we're going to draw out a
Zone here at this level we're going to
scroll up because we want to make sure
this has been tested at least two times
in the last 400 candles so if we scroll
left you can see that this area has in
fact been tested multiple times in the
last 400 candles so we have all the
criteria met for this to be a zone of
structure that I look for Possible
Trading opportunities inside of with
that being the case going to push the
market forward and eventually we get
this Candlestick pattern scenario we get
a long Wick to the top side with this
shooting star candle followed by a close
below candle so what this is telling us
is a lot of selling pressure coming out
of a zone that we know is likely to push
price down in a continuation of our
downtrend so with that being the case
this is where I would actually set up
the trade it would looks something like
this with a stop loss above our Zone
we'll use the same Target examples of a
1.4 to1 reward to risk ratio this is
where I would actually click the button
to place a sell trade and if we press
play you can see that price did in fact
eventually push down far enough to hit
those targets and this did in fact push
price lower into a continuation of this
downtrend so before we keep going I'm
going to explain this yesterday I was
riding around the city on one of those
electric scooters you can pay for and
someone walked right out in front of me
and I just swerve to miss them I fell
off the scooter ended up Landing
directly on on my face and although it
does hurt it looks way worse than it
feels so let's go ahead and continue
with the video what I'm going to do now
because this entire video has
essentially been me showing you trades
in hindsight that have already happened
that's just the nature of teaching
something that's what you have to do but
I want to give you guys what I'm looking
into for next week on the top five major
pairs utilizing the three strategies
you've learned throughout this entire
video so all this is not going to be in
hindsight there G to be things that have
not happened yet I'm just going to show
you how I'm preparing my Trading for
next week utilizing what you've learned
in this video on the top five major
pairs just before we do that if you've
enjoyed today's video then you would
likely enjoy the TTC forx University we
have some space available in the
University right now so if you'd like to
learn more about that it's going to be
the top Link in the description it's
essentially an entire course taking you
from beginner to Advanced strategies and
everything in between including risk
management and trading psychology
training and it also comes with two to
five of the trades I'm taking each week
sent directly to your email and it is a
mentorship program meaning any questions
you have about trading it'll be me
answering those questions personally so
if you're interested in that click the
top Link in the description if not let's
go ahe and take a look at the top five
major Pairs and walk through my exact
analysis utilizing these strategies on
those pairs first we're going to take a
look at the euro dollar on this pair
we're going to draw out our Trend we
have swing low to swing High down to
swing low up to our new swing High down
to our new swing low up to our new swing
High down to the swing low and up to the
new swing High where where are we at
right now we're in an uptrend because we
have not broken below or closed below
our previous swing low so with that
being the case we are currently in an
uptrend and do you notice any of the
strategies we talked about today coming
together right now hopefully you said
yes the bronze level strategy that you
just learned is happening right now here
on the euro dollar we have this area
which is our previous swing low before
the break into new highs and if we look
left this area has in fact been tested
and used multiple times by this pair so
with those two things coming together
this area is somewhere I'm looking into
right now for possible buy trades it
also helps that on the 4our chart we are
currently bouncing off of what our blue
line is our 50 EMA so with that being
the case we have kind of an A+ setup for
the bronze trading strategy so with that
being the case right now we've already
had an engulfing candle but as I said
earlier this is my least favorite of
these strategies and I need a lot of
confirmation in these areas for this
specific strategy so with that being
said I'm actually dropping down to the 1
hour chart and I'm waiting for a close
above candle after this double bottom
we've just gotten so on the 1 hour chart
we have a double bottom that is just
formed and I'm waiting for this candle
to possibly close above the previous
candle if that happens I'll personally
be placing a Buy trade here I'll
probably wait and do that or actually
I'll have to wait and do that on Monday
it's currently Friday and it's almost
5:00 p.m. but that's what I'm going to
be waiting on and that's the analysis
for the euro dollar utilizing the exact
strategy you just learned next up let's
take a look at the pound dollar and
first things first let's go ahead and
draw out our Trend we have swing low up
to swing High down to swing low up to
swing High down to swing low up to swing
high and what have we just done we have
just created a possible reversal
scenario the gold trading strategy it
obviously hasn't happened yet but but
it's very important to prepare for these
things you don't want to come onto
charts and just start guessing at where
you're supposed to be trading you want
to go ahead and be prepared for when
these things happen so that's what we're
doing right now in this case since we
have just had price come down and close
below that previous swing low we have a
possible reversal in Trend happening
right now so because of that what we're
going to be waiting for is price to pull
back up to this Zone this Zone has not
been tested multiple times looking left
but that's not a rule I have for this
specific strategy for the gold strategy
I don't need multiple times tested it
obviously adds accuracy but even without
that I'm still going to be looking for
price to come up here get between 1.
2959 and 1.29 37 and I'll be looking for
possible entries inside of this area for
the start of a new downtrend here on the
pound dollar and that's what I'm looking
at for this pair next up we're taking a
look at the dollar Yen here on this pair
we have a push lower to a swing low
lower swing High down to a lower swing
low so at this point what do you think
we're looking for we looking for two
Possible Trading strategies we're
looking for the silver or the bronze
trading strategy we're starting off with
the silver being this area right here
that price is currently in in this area
that has in fact been tested multiple
times looking left so that's our second
rule met what we're going to be looking
for is possible entries in this zone so
right now on the 4 Hour chart we have no
entry in this Zone based on the exact
entries that I look for again I'm going
to do a detailed video on that next up
so be sure you're subscribed and be sure
you have that notification Bell clicked
but let's drop down to the 1 hour chart
and see if we get anything here here I'd
be looking for something like a double
top we do not have a double top yet but
that's something I'll be keeping an eye
out for going into next week here on the
dollar Yen next up we are taking a look
at the dollar Swiss here on this pair we
have a push lower down to a swing low up
to a lower high down to a lower low up
to a lower high down to a lower low and
at this point we're in the midst of a
pullback in a downtrend meaning the
place I'm going to be looking for
possible trades for our Trend
continuation strategy the silver
strategy is going to be right here so
this is going to be the first place I
look for possible trades and it has in
fact been tested multiple times by price
in these areas so with that being the
case I have everything I need for this
to be a Zone I look for possible sell
trades inside of if this pullback
continues to this area this is where
I'll be looking for possible entries
this area is between 0 8942 and
0.892 4 and finally last but not least
let's look at the Aussie dollar here on
this pair we have a pushup to a swing
High higher low higher high equal low
higher high higher low higher high and
what have we just done we've just broken
and closed below this previous level so
in this case what strategy do we have
the opportunity to trade in this
situation this would be our gold
strategy or reversal strategy really
cool thing about this as well is that it
created a head and shoulders pattern
before pushing lower so if we get a
pullback to this area not only does it
meet the criteria for the reversal
trading strategy that we talked about at
the beginning of the video but also this
is the neckline of this head and
shoulders pattern so that's providing a
little more accuracy in this situation
so what I'll be waiting for next week on
this pair is a pullback into this area
between 0.67 35 and 0.672 3 inside of
the zone is where I'll be looking for
possible entries to get involved in a
trade to the downside and hopefully
capture the start of a new downtrend and
hopefully get a really good reward to
risk profile on this trade here on the
Aussie dollar I hope you enjoyed today's
video if you did make sure you click
that like button make sure to subscribe
if you are new to be alerted about the
video about entries I'm going to be
coming out with next also don't forget
if you're interested in the TTC Forex
University it'll be the top Link in the
description or you can go to www.
thetradingcarder
structure trading strategies and these
are by far my favorite and most accurate
Market structure trading strategies that
I utilize in my own personal trading so
again I hope you enjoyed it I hope you
trade green I wish you all the best of
luck in your future trading career and
I'll talk to you in the next video see
you soon